Juste Astrauskaite

Hammersmith, LONDON, W14 0HD ☎ 07901 858908
□ juste.astrauskaite@gmail.com

Portfolio juste.codes

Personal Profile

After working in various customer service roles for the past 10 years, I was seeking a career change where I would be continuously challenged. The idea of Software Development originated from my intention of creating an online drop shipping store, when I realised, I enjoyed customising my website theme more than anything else.

After going a self-taught route for a while, I enrolled in a self-funded technical training course which later led me to a twelve-week intensive bootcamp, where I completed projects using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, MongoDB and Python.

I am currently searching for a Junior Developer opportunity where I could develop as an IT professional and progress within a challenging environment.

Education and IT Training

11/2021-Present Just IT Training Ltd, London
--

Digital Skills Bootcamp: Software Development

A twelve-week intensive bootcamp covering the fundamentals of

Web and Software development.

04/2021-06/2021 Fashion Retail Academy, London, UK

Intensive Post-graduate course in Fashion Retail programme:

Buying, Merchandising and Management

09/2003-06/2007 ISM University of Management and Economics, Vilnius, Lithuania

BA in Management and Business Administration

Core Modules: Statistical Data Analysis, Customer Relationship Management,

Marketing Principles, Business Research Methods, Entrepreneurship,

Strategic Management, Financial Management

09/1991-06/2003 Didzdvaris gymnasium, Siauliai, Lithuania

IT Skills

Web Technology and Software Development Skills: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, C#, ASP.NET, MySQL, MongoDB, Python, Flask, Pandas

Projects:

Breathe and Relax App – a guided breathing/ambient sounds app. The user can pick the amount of time they want to use it and choose different ambient sounds. The app will let the user know when to breath in/hold/breathe out. This project was created using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Vegan wine checker - an app where a user can check if a certain wine is vegan friendly or not. It has a database of almost 6000 wines, which also can be updated by the user (add, delete, update functions as well as search). This project was created using Python, Pandas, MySQL, Flask and Bootstrap.

Employment History

02/2015-06/2021 Bershka Flagship, London, UK Visual Merchandiser

- Being solely responsible for the planning and building of store displays.
- Managing my own time by being organised and prioritise tasks to ensure the store is ready for opening.

- Monitoring and analysing sales records and consumer purchasing trends.
- Assisting with the training and development of all store employees on product knowledge, image and collections.
- Communicating with Product Managers and Buyers in the Central Offices about the store needs and giving feedback.
- Being flexible and supporting the team with other tasks, also supporting Visual Merchandisers in other stores when needed.
- Carrying out comparative shop reports on a regular basis.

03/2014-09/2014 Zara Flagship, Madrid, Spain InTransit Programme – Sales Assistant

• 6 months international exchange with a colleague from another store.

12/2011-02/2015 Zara Flagship, London, UK Deputy Head Cashier

- Dealing with customer queries in a calm and professional manner.
- Being responsible and accurate when performing bank deposits and withdrawals according to established policies.
- Training newly hired cashiers on accounting procedures and company policies.
- Ensuring customer transactions are processed promptly and accurately.
- Evaluating performance of cashiers and providing feedback.
- Generate cash related documents and account reports.
- Dealing with technical issues related to POS systems.

03/2011-12/2011 IZA Retail Ltd t/a MORI (Asian restaurant/takeaway), London, UK General Manager

- Fully in charge of 37 covers restaurant and takeaway shop with the YTD turnover of 630 K and an increase of 76 K compare to previous year.
- Fully in charge of ordering and stock take.
- Profit and loss accounting, forecasting, and planning.
- Ensuring rotas and time sheets are in line with budgets and expenditure.
- Where appropriate, coaching new members of the management team through the back office procedures, as part of their development.
- Fully conversant with company IT systems.
- Undertaking all daily and weekly banking and cash handling duties.

03/2010-03/2011 IZA Retail Ltd t/a MORI (Asian restaurant/takeaway), London, UK Supervisor / Assistant Manager

08/2007-01/2010 Ministry of Agriculture of the Republic of Lithuania, Vilnius, LT Chief Specialist in EU Affairs and International Relations Division

- Managing international projects: preparing monthly and quarterly financial reports; evaluating, preparing and presenting monitoring reports to the Ministry of Finances; organising steering committee meetings; mediating between Central Project Management Agency and Ministry of Agriculture regarding reports, payments and audit.
- Contributed to organising the conference "Progress and Perspectives of Rural Development Policy 2007-2013 Meeting 5th Anniversary of the EU Accession": content management, administrative and logistic tasks as well as liaising with international agencies.

Interests and Achievements

Computing: Thoroughly enjoy learning, especially new technologies. Long term Windows user with experience in Linux, recently switched to Mac and macOS. Always the first person to be called by family and work colleagues in case of any technical/computer issues.

Hobbies: I enjoy travelling and anything nature related. Passionate animal lover (therefore a vegan) who appreciates good food, and who never says 'no' to a quick DIY project.

References available upon request